Declan Greenhalgh

http://www.decln.com Email: dec@decln.com

Who I am:

I am a product owner/developer currently working in the Futures Technology space at NatWest Markets (RBS Group). I manage the stack's middleware application, which implements Java server/client methodologies, SQL and Unix, though I am equally keen on working with C# and Python.

I have followed an atypical route into software development/management, having come from a psychology background prior to my computer science education. This background complements my skills in software engineering, with my particular interests being in organisational capabilities, Agile practices and how to deliver high-value change on a regular basis.

I aim to continue growing in an application management role, but still want to preserve my technical skills. Potential career paths that interest me include enterprise architecture and developer management, but in these early stages of my career I would like to get a variety of experiences.

Education:

MSc. Computer Science, University of Kent, 2014 – 2015

Obtained a Master's degree in a programme covering a wide range of computing concepts, including: Java-based Object Oriented Programming, Web-Based Information Systems, Logic Programming, Machine Learning and Systems Architecture.

BSc. (Hons.) Psychology and Sociology, University of Kent, 2011-2014

Obtained a 2:1. Undertook two research projects in my final year, including a technical-based electroencephalography study in Psychology.

Lancaster Royal Grammar School, 2005-2011

Obtained an 'A' grade in History, and 'B' grades in Chemistry, French, Drama and General Studies A-Levels. Gained 12 GCSEs A*-C, including English Literature (A*), English Language (A) and Maths (A).

Employment:

MThree Consulting Ltd / NatWest Markets

Product Owner (September 2016 - Present)

- > Continuation of the below role, but owning the middleware application.
- Enhanced focus on application design, project management, stakeholder management, and providing services as the middleware SME.

Developer (September 2015 – August 2016)

- > Working primarily in a developer role based onsite at RBS, in the Futures Technology space.
- ➤ Day-to-day is working on the in-house Futures Execution & Clearing middleware that handles communication between the full F2B stack. Currently working on a major transformation project due to a 3rd-party vendor switch, working on the entire lifecycle in an agile environment.
- ➤ Have been responsible for the implementation of CMMI within my application.
- > Technologies used include Java, FIX Protocol, C#, SQL, Unix and a variety of agile tools.

University of Kent Information Services

Assistant Support Desk Supervisor (September 2014 – August 2015)

- ➤ Role included supervisory & SME aspects.
- > Required to manage the University IT services at the weekend and out of hours.

IT and Library Support Desk Assistant (April 2013 – September 2014)

- ➤ Customer-facing helpdesk role helping with technical issues.
- ➤ Helped develop my abilities to deal with a range of customers, communicating with relevant colleagues and maintaining a presentable, professional work environment.

Professional Affiliations:

- > British Psychological Society, with a title of MBPsS. Part of the Division of Occupational Psychology.
- ➤ British Computing Society, with the title of AMBCS. Member of additional Specialist Groups including Software Process Improvement Network, Software Practice Advancement, Agile Methods, Financial Services and Advanced Programming.

Additional Information & Interests

- > I enjoy playing the piano in my spare time.
- > Treasurer and committee member of the University's trampolining team for two years.
- > British Gymnastics' qualified judge, and have judged at national competitions to an elite level.
- > Received Green Colours from Kent Sport for the administrative service I provided to the club.